So first we will program our STM eight microcontroller.
So this is the exact model number of STM eight microcontroller.
There are thousands of microcontroller, so you have to remember the number.
Exactly.
So this is the model number of our microcontroller, which is STM eight as 0033.
So this is a microcontroller which is on this MFC 522 board.
Right.
So we will program this microcontroller first and to program this microcontroller, we just need to
upload hex file to this STM 8003 F3 microcontroller and using this stm8 and Stm32 USB.
So this is what we are going to do next.
So let me first show you the connection, how you are going to make the connection.
So make sure you have placed the boat in the same position as shown in the screenshot over here.
So make sure the connection is made from the crystal side.
As you can see, the crystal and basically there are two types of header, the mail headers.
The first one is over here and the other one is over here through which we have made our connection.
This header Prince over here is used to make the connection through USB to TTL, which we are going
to see next.
First we have to, you know, update our.
First, we have to program our STM eight microcontroller and to program this microcontroller we have
to use swim header pins.
These are called swim header pins which are near the crystal and the USB to TTL.
Connection is from the test point.
If you position the board as it is shown over here, you will see that test point is written on the
board.
So you make sure you don't make connection from test point.
You have to make connection from swim side, right?
This is the point to remember.
And then we have to make the connection from our USB that STM eight and STM 32 USB.
So by the way, this board operates on five volts, right?
So you can connect five volts easily with this USB.
So first you have to make connection on five volts which is over here on pin nine and you can make a
connection on five volt.
And then there is a swim pin which is on pin five.
So you have to make a connection to the swim pin of this port, which is on number two.
Right?
Then there is a ground pin and then there is a reset pin.
So it's quite simple connection.
It's not that hard to make a connection.
So you can see it over here as well.
I have made the connection and I have just placed the USB in my laptop so you can see that as well.
So now let's just do our programming on this microcontroller.
Let me move into my machine.
So the first tool which I have shown in my previous slide was Steve.
Steve, my programmer.
So this is the tool so you can install this tool easily.
There are a few clicks you have to do and this tool will install.
So let's just open this tool.
After opening this tool.
There is a small button over here right behind this box, so you have to click on this box to select
the exact microcontroller which we are using.
So first you have to select Stty dash, link this option.
Then from the ports option, you have to select USB.
Then in USB port option, there is another option programming mode.
We are using swim programming mode as we have made a swim connection.
So you have to select swim.
And then over here, as you can see, there are lots of models.
So our model is stm8.
S and zero zero.
So let's just select that port stems and zero zero over here.
And our board is.
Eight.
S0033.
This is the model number of the board which we are using the model number of our microcontroller, which
we are using.
So you just have to select this microcontroller.
And press.
Okay.
So the microcontroller is selected and you can see it over here as well.
Now, what you have to do is you have to.
Uh, upload the hex file.
Right.
So the hex file is provided with the tool and the link is provided in the resources file.
The two links which I have provided in the resources file, as I have shown you in my previous video.
So you have to download those two softwares and this hex file is included in this software as well.
So all you have to do is you have to just select that hex file, which is RC 522 hex, and this file
is included.
I'm just repeating one more time, so you just have to download and select.
You don't have to program this file.
This file is already included, so I'll just select this file.
And the hex file is loaded.
And over here you can see there are basically three tabs program, memory tab, data, memory tab and
option byte.
First, you have to select option byte and all you have to do is make sure read out protection is off.
If it's on, you will not be able to program this card correctly.
So make sure this read out protection is off and selecting the same option byte.
What you have to do is you have to click the second option, which is the burn option.
So it will burn this byte on the on the microcontroller so that it's able to read the program and write
the program on the flash memory.
So make sure this read out protection is off.
And let's just click this second option to burn the this bit.
And over here you can see option bytes successfully verified.
That means the option byte is written successfully.
And now we can do our program memory and we can program our board.
So all you have to do is you have to just select after selecting the program memory option from this
tab, you have to again, burn this program, right?
So we will burn this program with the same command or the same button over here.
And you can see program memory successfully verified.
So that means the program is written successfully.
Right.
So this is how you write a program using a microcontroller.
And we have written the program successfully.
In the next video, we are going to see how we will make our connection using USB to cable and then
we will see how to update our Mifare classic cards, right?
So we will see our connection for USB two cable in the next video.